92. Capoeira, The Dance of War. Capoeira is a unique combination of music,
dance, sport, fighting, and competition. This distinct art form comes from Brazil. Slaves
and the descendants of slaves created Capoeira, which is also influenced by the culture of
native people of Brazil. In the 1600s, the rulers of Brazil were bringing slaves from
Africa to work on huge farms. These slaves began to form their own culture. This new
culture combined arts from Africa and Brazil, creating Capoeira. The music and dance probably
helped tell stories and bind people together. But the slaves who developed Capoeira would
have wanted to be free. Experts think the fighting in Capoeira may have been a way for
slaves to train to escape or revolt. They hid their war training inside music and dance,
and then used it to help themselves survive in the jungle or fight against their owners. Capoeira
has been called the dance of war. Capoeira now is performed by two people who dance with and
compete against each other. The competition is called the Jogo. The Jogo is performed like a
battle, but the battle is fought to the rhythm of a traditional stringed instrument called a
barrambao. The performers use kicks and leg-sweeping movements to fight. They also use
headbutts, cartwheels, handstands, and other acrobatic moves. They take turns moving forward
and falling back, as in a battle. They duck to escape kicks. The goal is never to injure one's
opponent. Rather, the idea is to catch one's opponent off guard and show the fighting move
that could have hurt him. Capoeira is about showing skill, not winning and losing. Capoeira
is becoming popular around the world because it teaches fitness and grace. You may find this
dance of war from the days of slavery in your town soon.